Guide to the Institute of Pacific Relations Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Institute of Pacific Relations Records
1927-1962.
Institute of Pacific Relations.
232 linear ft. (ca.235,050 items in 476 boxes, 59 volumes, & 2 oversize folders).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079192
History
The Institute of Pacific Relations (IPR) was an international NGO established in 1925 to provide a forum for discussion of problems and relations between nations of the Pacific Rim. The Institute dissolved in 1960.
Scope and Content
The office files of the American Institute of Pacific Relations and the international Institute of Pacific Relations, containing correspondence and reports concerned with international conferences, research programs, and publications programs of both Institutes, and relating to the political, economic, and social problems in eastern and southern Asia and the South Pacific, as well as with problems of American foreign policy. There are many travel letters and on-the-spot reports relating to conditions in China, Japan, Russia, Australia, the Philippines, India, and Pakistan during the period 1933 to 1954.
1990 Addition: I.P.R. materials found in the Papers of Sen. Joseph McCarthy at Marquette University have been added.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged. The collection is arranged in nine parts, with oversized materials following at the end of the collection.
Part I, Cataloged Materials & the Pacific Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations
Cataloged correspondence & manuscripts (Boxes A-B)
Pacific Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations (Boxes 1-100)
Part II, American Institute of Pacific Relations,1926-1959, & misc. committee files (Boxes 101-295)
Part III, Files of individuals (Boxes 296-340)
Part IV, McCarran Committee files (Boxes 341-381)
Part V, Financial records (Boxes 382-439)
Part VI, Publications (Boxes 440-446)
Part VII, Miscellaneous Files (Boxes 447-456)
Part VIII, Conference documents and papers (Boxes 457-472)
Part IX, McCarthy Committee files (Boxes 473-474)
Oversized materials
Subjects
Institute of Pacific Relations.--American Council.; American Institute of Pacific Relations.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Carter, Edward C. (Edward Clark), 1878-1954.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989.; McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957.; United States--Foreign relations--Pacific Area--Societies, etc.; Pacific Area--Foreign relations--United States--Societies, etc.; South Asia--Social conditions.; East Asia--Social conditions.; Oceania--Social conditions.; China--Social conditions.; Japan--Social conditions.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; Australia--Social conditions.; Philippines--Social conditions.; India--Social conditions.; Pakistan--Social conditions.; Social problems.; World politics.; Agenda.; Annual reports.; Applications.; Articles.; Audits.; Bibliographies.; Budgets.; Bulletins.; Bylaws.; Card files.; Certificates.; Constitutions.; Contracts.; Dockets.; Essays.; Financial documents and records.; Interviews.; Invitations.; Ledgers.; Lists.; Maps.; Memoranda.; Minutes.; Notes.; Personnel records.; Photographs.; Photoprints.; Press releases.; Proceedings.; Questionnaires.; Reports.; Resumes.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.; Testimonials.; Transcripts.; Area specialists.; Developing countries specialists.; International relations specialists.; Internationalists.; Japanologists.; Orientalists.; Political scientists.; Sinologists.
The following boxes are located off-site: 1-474. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1961 M-61 American Institute of Pacific Relations and International Institute of Pacific Relations through William L. Holland and Mary F. Healy Gift
07/09/90 M-90-07-09 Papers from Joseph McCarthy Collection Marquette University Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letters are on microfilm.
Gift of the American Institute of Pacific Relations and International Institute of Pacific Relations via William L. Holland & Mary F. Healy, 1961.
Gift of F. Hamburger, Jr. of Johns Hopkins University, Archives, 1981.
Gift of Marquette University, 1990.
Related Material
J.B.(John Bell) Condliffe. Reminiscences of the Institute of Pacific Relations. Vancouver, B.C.: Institute of Asian Research, University of British Columbia, 1981
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Edward C. Carter Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Selected Related Material-- Other Repositories
Edward C. Carter Papers, University of Vermont.
William W. Lockwood Papers, Princeton University. The files of William W. Lockwood concerning the Institute for the years 1946-1962, are in the Archives, Firestone Library, Princeton University. His files for 1935-1940 and 1941-1943 are in the Columbia collection.
Brooks Emeny Papers, Princeton University. Emeny was a member of the Board of Trustees of the American Council, IPR.
Institute of Pacific Relations fonds, University of British Columbia, Vancouver.
Institute of Pacfic Relations Records, University of Hawaii.
Institute of Pacific Relations. San Francisco Bay Region Division Records, Hoover Institution.
Finding aid in repository and online.
- Part I: Cataloged Materials & the Pacific Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations
  - Part I.1 Cataloged Correspondence
    - Acheson, Dean (Box A-B)
    - Baker, Newton Diehl (Box A-B)
    - Baldwin, Roger Nash (Box A-B)
    - Bolton, Frances P. (Box A-B)
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Box A-B)
      (Also available on microfilm MN# 91-2094-2)
    - Bunche, Ralph (Box A-B)
    - Chiang, Mayling Soong (Mme. Chiang Kai-shek) (Box A-B)
    - Davis, Malcolm W (Box A-B)
    - Dulles, Foster Rhea (Box A-B)
    - Dulles, John Foster (Box A-B)
    - Earle, Edward Mead (Box A-B)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B. (Box A-B)
    - Fulbright, J. William (Box A-B)
    - Gilchrist, Huntington (Box A-B)
    - Greene, Jerome D. (Box A-B)
    - Gromyko, Andrei A. (Box A-B)
    - Gulick, Luther (Box A-B)
    - Gunther, John (Box A-B)
    - Hand, Learned (Box A-B)
    - Harriman, W. Averell (Box A-B)
    - Hepburn, Katharine (Box A-B)
    - Hersey, John (Box A-B)
    - Hiss, Alger (Box A-B)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello H. (Box A-B)
    - Lasker, Bruno (Box A-B)
    - Lerner, Max (Box A-B)
    - Lippmann, Walter (Box A-B)
    - Luce, Henry R. (Box A-B)
    - Mead, Margaret (Box A-B)
    - Murrow, Edward R. (Box A-B)
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal (Box A-B)
    - Nevins, Allen (Box A-B)
    - Plimpton, Francis T.P. (Box A-B)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (Box A-B)
    - Rockefeller, John D., III (Box A-B)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box A-B)
    - Sproul, Robert G. (Box A-B)
    - Stimson, Henry L. (Box A-B)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays (Box A-B)
    - Tawney, Richard Henry (Box A-B)
    - Thomas, Lowell (Box A-B)
    - Toynbee, Arnold J. (Box A-B)
    - Wagner, Robert F. (Box A-B)
    - Wallace, Henry A. (Box A-B)
    - Warburg, James P. (Box A-B)
    - Welles, Sumner (Box A-B)
    - White, Theodore H. (Box A-B)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box A-B)
    - Willkie, Wendell L. (Box A-B)
    - Young, Owen D. (Box A-B)
  - Part I.2 Cataloged Manuscripts
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Box B)
  - Part I.3 Uncataloged Office Files
    - Pacific Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations
      These are arranged chronologically, and then A-Z by subject.
      - 1935-1936 and earlier
        - American Council Annual Meeting
          - 1934 October 25 (Box 1)
          - 1935 (Box 1)
          - 1936 December 18 (Box 1)
        - American Council
          - Frederick V. Field Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1)
          - Financial Statements (Box 1)
          - General File (Box 1)
          - Membership (Box 1)
          - Russian Language Projects (Box 1)
          - Staff--Shiman, Wiss, Earnshaw, Lockwood (Box 1)
        - Basic English--Charlotte Tyler (Box 1)
        - Bibliographical Project
          - General Correspondence (Box 1)
          - Comments (Box 1)
          - Memoranda (Box 2)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
        - Canada (Box 2)
        - Carter, William D. (Box 2)
        - Chicago--Finance and Membership (Box 2)
        - Contribution Lists (Box 2)
        - Constitutions (unrevised) (Box 2)
        - Curtis, Davis, Greene Correspondence - 1929 (Box 2)
        - Finance Campaign - Background Material (Box 2)
        - Fisher, Galen M. (2 Folders) (Box 2)
        - Manchouko--Soviet Border Issue (Box 2)
        - San Francisco Office-- Cora Hartdegen (Box 2)
        - San Francisco - Portland - Seattle (Box 2)
        - U (Box 2)
        - USSR
          - General Files (Box 2)
          - Motylev, Voitinsky (Box 3)
          - Soviet Council (Box 3)
        - University of Chicago Press--Contracts, 1982-1932 (Box 3)
        - V (Box 3)
        - W (Box 3)
        - Wittfogel, Dr. Karl A. (Box 3)
        - X-Y-Z (Box 3)
        - Young, Hobart N. (Box 3)
      - 1937
        - A (Box 4)
        - American Council Executive Committee (Box 4)
        - American Council General File (Box 4)
        - American Council Staff (Box 4)
        - American Russian Institute (Box 4)
        - Applications (Box 4)
        - Australian Council (Box 4)
        - B (Box 4)
        - Barnett, Mr. & Mrs. W. O. (Box 4)
        - Borton, Hugh (Box 4)
        - Brunauer, Esther Caukin (Box 4)
        - C (Box 4)
        - Carter, E.C.
          - General (Box 5)
          - Expense Account (Box 5)
          - Notes of speeches (Box 5)
          - Personal File (Box 5)
        - Chen Han-seng (Box 5)
        - China
          - General File (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 5)
          - Notes on 1937 visit (Box 5)
        - China Council--Liu Yu-wan, Hu Shih (Box 5)
        - China Society of America (Box 5)
        - D (Box 5)
        - E (Box 5)
        - F (Box 6)
        - Field, Frederick Y. (3 Folders) (Box 6)
        - Finance--Foundations
          - Carnegie Corporation
            - F.P. Keppel (Box 6)
            - R.M. Lester (Box 6)
          - Carnegie Endowment
            - N.M. Butler (Box 6)
            - H.S. Haskell (Box 6)
          - Payne Fund
            - Ella Crandall (Box 6)
            - S.H. Evans (Box 6)
          - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 6)
          - Rosenwald Fund
            - E.R. Embree (Box 6)
            - L. Rosenwald (Box 6)
        - Financial Statements--Contribution Lists (Box 6)
        - French Council
          - Roger Levy (Box 6)
          - Albert Sarraut (Box 6)
        - G (Box 7)
        - Gift Letters (Box 7)
        - H (Box 7)
        - Holland, W. L. (Box 7)
        - Hong Kong Visit--Notes (Box 7)
        - I (Box 7)
        - J (Box 7)
        - K (Box 7)
        - L (Box 8)
        - Lattimore, Owen (Box 8)
        - M (Box 8)
        - Mitchell, Kate (Box 8)
        - Moscow Trial--Clippings (Box 8)
        - N (Box 8)
        - Netherland Council (Box 8)
        - Netherlands General File (Box 8)
        - New Zealand Council (Box 8)
        - O (Box 8)
        - P (Box 9)
        - Pacific Affairs (Box 9)
        - Philippines Council
          - C. Benitez (Box 9)
          - M. Camus (Box 9)
        - Philippine Visit - Notes (Box 9)
        - Publications Office - New York (Box 9)
        - Publications Office - Shanghai (Box 9)
        - Pyke, Richard (Box 9)
        - R (Box 9)
        - Royal Institute of International Affairs
          - Ivison Macadam (Box 9)
          - Archibald Rose (Box 9)
        - S (Box 9)
        - San Francisco Office (Box 10)
        - Social Science Research Council (Box 10)
        - Southern California Group (Box 10)
        - T (Box 10)
        - Tickler (Box 10)
        - U (Box 10)
        - U.S. Foreign Policy--Clippings (Box 10)
        - USSR
          - General File (Box 10)
          - V. E. Motylev (Box 10)
          - Y. P. Bremman (Box 10)
          - E. V. Harondar (Box 10)
        - V (Box 10)
        - W (Box 10)
        - X - Y - Z (Box 10)
      - 1938
        - Alexander, A. V. (Box 11)
        - Allen, Devere - No Frontier News Service (Box 11)
        - Alsberg, Dr. Carl L. (Box 11)
        - American Council Membership and Finance (Box 11)
        - American Russian Institute (Box 11)
        - Austern, Hilda (Box 11)
        - Australian Institute of International Affairs
          - W. Eggleston (Box 11)
          - P. R. Heydon (Box 11)
        - B (Box 11)
        - Bloch, Dr. Kurt (Box 11)
        - C (Box 12)
        - Canadian Institute of International Affairs
          - Escott Reid (Box 12)
          - Escott Reid (Box 12)
          - J. W. Dafoe (Box 12)
        - Canadian Institute of International Affairs General File (Box 12)
        - Carter, Alice (Mrs. Edward C.) (Box 12)
        - Carter, E. C.--Personal (Box 12)
        - Carter Family Correspondence (Box 12)
        - Case, Everett (Box 12)
        - Chang, P.C. (Box 12)
        - Chen, Han-seng (Box 12)
          [File missing as of 1996]
        - Chi, Ch’ao-ting (Box 12)
        - Chicago Casino Club--Follow-up (Box 12)
        - China Council
          - Hu Shih (Box 13)
          - Liu Yu Wan (Box 13)
        - China Institute in America - Office Reports (Box 13)
        - Civilian Relief in China - United Council (Box 13)
        - Cleeve, Margaret (Box 13)
        - Condliffe, J. B. (Box 13)
        - Conference Plans for 1939 (Box 13)
        - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 13)
        - D (Box 13)
        - Dafoe, J.W. (Box 13)
        - Data Papers (Box 14)
        - Dennery, Etienne (Box 14)
        - Downing, Elizabeth (Box 14)
        - Dulles, John Foster (Box 14)
        - E (Box 14)
        - Emeny, Brooks (Box 14)
        - Exchange Service (Box 14)
        - F (Box 14)
        - Fairfax--Gholmeley, Elsie (Box 14)
        - Farley, Miriam (Box 14)
        - Finance--Foundations
          - Carnegie Corporation
            - P. Keppel (Box 14)
            - R. M. Lester (Box 14)
          - Carnegie Endowment
            - N. M. Butler (Box 14)
            - H. S. Haskell (Box 14)
          - Payne Fund
            - E. P. Crandall (Box 14)
            - H. S. Evans (Box 14)
          - Rockefeller Foundation
            - S. Walker (Box 14)
            - S. M. Gunn (Box 14)
            - D. H. Stevens (Box 14)
            - J. Marshall (Box 14)
            - R. Fosdick (Box 14)
          - Rosenwald Fund
            - E. S. Embree (Box 14)
        - Fisher, Galen M. (Box 14)
        - Form Letters--Distribution (Box 14)
        - Freidman, Irving S. (Box 14)
        - French Council
          - Albert Sarraut (Box 14)
          - Roger Levy (Box 14)
          - Comite d’Etudes des Problemes du Pacifique (Box 14)
        - G (Box 15)
        - Garside, B. A. (Box 15)
        - General Policy (Box 15)
        - Gepp, Sir Herbert (Box 15)
        - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 15)
        - Greene, Roger S. (Box 15)
        - H (Box 15)
        - Hawaiian--Group (Box 15)
        - Holland, William L. (Box 15)
        - Holland, William L--Memo on the IPR Organization (Box 16)
        - Hu Shih (Box 16)
        - Hubbard, G. E. (Box 16)
        - I-J (Box 16)
        - IPR Notes (Box 16)
        - International Labor Office (Box 16)
        - International Secretariat (Box 16)
        - International Secretariat Inquiry
          - National Council Cooperation (Box 16)
          - Statements of Project. Outlines (Box 16)
        - International Studies Conference--General Correspondence (Box 16)
        - Jackson, Mrs. Henry B. (Box 16)
        - Japan and the Chinese War (Box 16)
        - Java Tiffin Club (Box 16)
        - Jessup, Philip C. (Box 17)
        - K (Box 17)
        - L (Box 17)
        - Lasker, Bruno (Box 17)
        - League of Nations Secretariat
          - J. Avenol (Box 17)
          - Condliffe (Box 17)
          - Kullmann (Box 17)
          - Sweetser (Box 17)
        - Liang, Hubert S. (Box 17)
        - Lilienthal, Philip E. (Box 17)
        - Lockwood, W, W. (Box 17)
        - Loomis, Charles F. (Box 17)
        - M (Box 17)
        - McClatchy, V. S. (Box 17)
        - MacDonald, Ross (Box 17)
        - MacKenzie, Norman (Box 17)
        - Mallory, Walter H. (Box 17)
        - Map Project (Box 17)
        - Markoe, Mrs. Harry (Box 17)
        - Max, F. (Box 17)
        - Mayeda, Tamon (Box 17)
        - Meherally, Yusuf (Box 17)
        - Milner, Ian (Box 18)
        - Mitchell, Kate (Box 18)
        - Mitrany, David (Box 18)
        - Moerman, Elodie (Box 18)
        - Moll, J. Th (Box 18)
        - Moore, Harriet (Box 18)
        - Morgan, Shepard (Box 18)
        - Morrisson, Mrs. James W. (Box 18)
        - Morrisson, W. D. F. (Box 18)
        - N-O (Box 18)
        - Netherlands--NEI, IPR
          - DeBussy (Box 18)
          - J. H. Boeke (Box 18)
        - New Zealand IPR
          - Sir James Allen (Box 18)
          - Bruce Turner (Box 18)
        - Norman, E. H. (Box 18)
        - Oakie, John H. (Box 18)
        - Orrick, William H., Jr. (Box 18)
        - Oumansky, Constantine (Box 18)
        - P-Q (Box 18)
        - Parker, Philo W. (Box 18)
        - Parkin, G. R. (Box 18)
        - Peffer, Nathaniel (Box 18)
        - Peters, Capt. Richard (Box 18)
        - Philippine Council
          - V. Madrigal (Box 18)
          - Maxey (Box 18)
          - General File (Box 18)
        - Population in American Cities from I.P.R. Member Countries (Box 19)
        - Price, Ernest B. (Box 19)
        - Price, Harry B. (Box 19)
        - Price, Waterhouse and Co (Box 19)
        - Princeton Conference
          - 1938 April 23-24 (Box 19)
          - 1938 December 29-1939 January 5 (Box 19)
          - Secretariat Report (Box 19)
        - Princeton Reporter Notes (Box 19)
        - Pyke, Richard L. (Box 19)
        - Pyke, R. L. - Replies to Memorial Letter (Box 19)
        - R (Box 19)
        - Randolph, Jeannette (Box 19)
        - Raymond, Elizabeth (Box 19)
        - Reid, Escott (Box 19)
        - ReQua, Eloise (Box 19)
        - Rhoads, Charles J. (Box 19)
        - Rhodes, E. E. W. (Box 19)
        - Rowell, Ne-wton W. (Box 19)
        - Royal Institute of International Affair
          - I. S. Macadam (Box 19)
          - Archibald Rose (Box 19)
          - Neill Malcolm (Box 19)
          - John Chancellor (Box 19)
          - General File (Box 19)
        - Royse, M.W. (Box 19)
        - S (Box 20)
        - Sachs, Alexander (Box 20)
        - Salter, Sir Arthur (Box 20)
        - Sansom, Sir George (Box 20)
        - Scheffer, Paul (Box 20)
        - Scherer, James A. B. (Box 20)
        - Shepherd, Jack (Box 20)
        - Shillinglaw, David L. (Box 20)
        - Shiman, Russell (Box 20)
        - Shotwell, James T. (Box 20)
        - Smith, Jessica (Box 20)
        - South Manchuria Railway Company (Box 20)
        - Spalding, Eliot (Box 20)
        - Sproul, Robert G. (Box 20)
        - Staff--Contracts (Box 20)
        - Staley, Eugene (Box 20)
        - Standing Committees of the Institute (Box 20)
        - State Department (Box 20)
        - Steamship Sailings (Box 20)
        - Stelzle, Charles (Box 20)
        - Stephens, Waldo E. (Box 20)
        - Stuart, J. Leighton (Box 20)
        - Stubbs, Kathryn (Box 20)
        - Suma, Yakichiro (Box 20)
        - T (Box 20)
        - Takaki, Y. (Box 20)
        - Takayanagi, Kenzo (Box 20)
        - Taketa, Taneo (Box 20)
        - Takeuchi, Tatsuji (Box 20)
        - Tawney, R. R. (Box 20)
        - Taylor, George E. (Box 20)
        - Taylor, Margaret R. (Box 21)
        - Thompson, Virginia (Box 21)
        - Timperley, H. J. (Box 21)
        - Tobias, C. H. (Box 21)
        - Toronto Meeting, 1938 November (Box 21)
        - Trewartha, Glenn T. (Box 21)
        - Tsuru, Shigeto (Box 21)
        - Tsurumi, Yusuke (Box 21)
        - 215 East Seventy-second Street (Box 21)
        - 210 East sixty-eighth Street (Box 21)
        - Tyler, Charlotte (Box 21)
        - U-V (Box 21)
        - U.S. General File (Box 21)
        - U.S.S.R. General File (Box 21)
        - van Kleeck, Mary (Box 21)
        - W (Box 22)
        - Walsh, Richard J. (Box 22)
        - Welling, Mr. and Mrs. John Paul (Box 22)
        - White, Theodore H. (Box 22)
        - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 22)
        - H. W. Wilson Company
          - Johanna Kramm (Box 22)
        - Wint, Guy (Box 22)
        - Wiss, Helen (Box 22)
        - Wittfogel, Karl August (Box 22)
        - Wolfers, Arnold (Box 22)
        - Wood, Henry (Box 22)
        - World's Fair--New York (Box 22)
        - Wright, Quincy (Box 22)
        - X - Y - Z (Box 22)
        - Yamakawa, Tadao (Box 22)
        - Yasuo, Nagaharu (Box 22)
        - Young, Hobart (Box 22)
        - Young, Oven D. (Box 22)
      - 1939
        - A (Box 23)
        - Allen, G. C. (Box 23)
        - Alsberg, Carl L. (Box 23)
        - American Russian Institute (Box 23)
        - Anderson, Paul B.--"Russian News Bulletin" (Box 23)
        - Angus, H. F. (Box 23)
        - Atherton, Frank C. (Box 23)
        - Austern, Hilda (Box 23)
        - Australian Institute of International Affairs (Box 23)
        - Avarna di Gualtieri, Carlo (Box 23)
        - B (Box 23)
        - Barnes, Kathleen (Box 23)
        - Belshaw, H. (Box 23)
        - Bertram, James (Box 23)
        - Bisson, T. A. (Box 24)
        - Bloch, Dr. Kurt (Box 24)
        - Blumenthal, Annette (Box 24)
        - Boggeri, Maria Luisa (Box 24)
        - Borton, Hugh (Box 24)
        - Boulderwood Briarcliff Manor (Box 24)
        - British Columbia (Box 24)
        - Buell, Raymond Leslie (Box 24)
        - Burdick, Virginia (Box 24)
        - C (Box 24)
        - Canadian Institute of International Affairs
          - J. R. Baldwin (Box 24)
          - J. W. Dafoe (Box 24)
        - Carlson, Evans F. (Box 24)
        - Carter, Alice (Mrs. Edward C.) (Box 24)
        - Carter, Edward C.--Personal (Box 24)
        - Carter Family Correspondence (Box 24)
        - Cavalier Hotel (Box 24)
        - Chamberlin, William Henry--Newspaper Articles (Box 25)
        - Chang, P.C. (Box 25)
        - Chen, Han-seng (Box 25)
        - Chi, Ch’ao-ting (Box 25)
        - Chiang, Mayling Soong (Mme. Chiang Kai-shek)--War Orphans (Box 25)
        - China Council
          - Dr. Hu Shih (Box 25)
          - Liu Yu-wan (Box 25)
        - China Institute in America (Box 25)
        - China Institute in America (Box 25)
        - China Relief Appeals (Box 25)
        - Clark, Evans (Box 25)
        - Claxton, Brooke (Box 25)
        - Cleeve, Margaret (Box 25)
        - Condliffe, J. B. (Box 25)
        - Council on Foreign (Box 25)
        - D (Box 26)
        - Datta, S. K. (Box 26)
        - Dennery, Etienne (Box 26)
        - Distribution of Conference Documents (Box 26)
        - Distribution of Form Letters (Box 26)
        - E (Box 26)
        - Eggleston, Fred W. (Box 26)
        - Eichelberger, Clark M. (Box 26)
        - Emeny, Brooks (Box 26)
        - F (Box 26)
        - Fahs, Charles B. (Box 26)
        - Fairfax-Cholmeley, Elsie (Box 26)
        - Farley, Miriam S. (Box 26)
        - Faymonville, Philip R. (Box 26)
        - Finance--Foundations
          - Carnegie Corporation
            - R. Keppel (Box 27)
            - R. M. Lester (Box 27)
          - Carnegie Endowment
            - N. M. Butler (Box 27)
            - H. S. Haskell (Box 27)
          - Rockefeller Foundation
            - S. Walker (Box 27)
            - S. M. Gunn (Box 27)
            - D. H. Stevens (Box 27)
            - J. Marshall (Box 27)
            - R. Fosdick (Box 27)
        - Fisher, Galen M. (Box 27)
        - Fisheries Project (Box 27)
        - Foreign Policy Association Bulletins (Box 27)
        - Form Letter File (Box 27)
        - French Council (Box 27)
        - Friedman, Irving S. (Box 27)
        - G (Box 27)